MEKHLA MOHAN LEAD DATA **GOVERNANCE** ANALYST

- **4** 248-210-5032
- **♀** Troy, MI 48085
- in mekhla-mohan-18a0a275
- nekmoh8

Experienced Lead Business Intelligence/Data Governance Analyst with a Master's degree in Mathematics pursuing Data Science to make organizations become efficient & effective. Completed Springboard's Data Science Track mastering the data science process, from statistics and data wrangling, to advanced topics like machine learning and data storytelling.

Skills

MACHINE LEARNING

Sentiment Analysis

Text Classification

Time-Series Analysis

ALGORITHM

Naïve Baves

Random Forest

Regression

Classification Algorithm

Sentiment Analysis

ARIMA

TECHNOLOGIES

Tensor Flow

Google Pytrends

Twitter API

sklearn

TECHNICAL ENVIRONMENT

Python

Oracle SQL Oracle PL/SQL

JSP, ASP, JavaScript, Java, HTML, perl , shell scripts

Cognos Reports

Crystal Reports

Education

Springboard

Data Science Track

Pandit Ravishankar Shukla University

Masters Mathematics Bachelors Mathematics

National Institute of Information Technology Post-Graduate Diploma in Systems Management

Kimball University

Data WareHouse LifeCvcle

Oracle University

Data ware House Fundamentals

New Horizon

Project Management

Employment

Flagstar Bank

a Governance Analyst

Troy, MI Feb 2018 to Current

Develop, document, and implement data quality rules, policies, procedures and standards, dashboards, business glossary, data dictionary, etc. Acts as a Subject Matter Expert for data within the Data Warehouse and Data Mart

Performs root cause analysis to resolve data discrepancies or troubleshoot systemic anomalies

Create and monitor data quality scorecards and data integrity efforts to works with data owners/stewards to resolve data quality issues Perform data profiling and root cause analysis to identify data quality issues opportunities and provide recommendations to work with business and IT for remediation

Maintain detailed documentation including business glossaries, data dictionaries, data lineage and data rules In Collibra

Health Alliance Plan

Lead Business Intelligence Analyst

Southfield, MI May 2012 to Feb. 2018

Lead highly complex, cross functional, and enterprise IT and business intelligence solutions

Performed intensive analysis for a wide range of requests using data in different formats and from various platforms

Performed root-cause analysis and recommended solution for the data governance and quality issues using SOL

Published various list, crosstab, charts using Cognos Report Studio

Published data quality metrics, healthcare analytics dashboard using Cognos Report Studio

Automated ongoing standard SQL reports to ETL jobs/Cognos reports

Explored data and discover patterns, meaningful relationships, anomalies and trend using SQL

Recommended leadership to improve the design and development process and delivery of reports and dashboards using Cognos reports and **PowerBI**

Recommend healthcare quality metrics using SQL and ensure quality metrics are documented and tracked

Provided leadership to the project team to ensure that best practices are followed for BI, data warehousing, and data governance

Lead Systems Analyst

Southfield, MI April 2003 to May 2012

Executed all project management activities to ensure projects meet budget, timing and quality requirements

Promoted and managed team interaction and communication with minimal management intervention

Implemented new/upgraded codes, trained customers, and supported multiple groups during roll-out

Led the upgrade of IT Service management application software which entailed implementation of Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) and converting the database from a proprietary database (P4) to a relational database management system (ORACLE) Managed an initiative to standardize Crystal Reports version, which resulted in the implementation of an enterprise reporting tool, Crystal Reports Server XI, that provided a single platform to manage and distribute reports over the intranet

Evaluated/purchased/implemented a third-party vendor tools (Bursting Manager, APOS KPI) to integrate Crystal Reports Server XI Created multiple complex Crystal reports, Procedures, Triggers, and Views on databases

Directed the integration of a PowerBuilder application with the change and configuration management tool (CCC/Harvest)

Developed user-friendly web generated Project management dashboard which is a communication vehicle for proactive planning and risk mitigation. Developed several reports using JSP, ASP, JavaScript, Java, HTML, perl/ shell scripts.

Minacs

lune 2000 to Dec. 2002

Managed an Oracle database driven Wholesale Parts Marketing program for an automotive manufacturer which included leading a team of analysts, assisting analysts with roadblocks and project management.

Syntel

rammer Analyst

lan, 1996 to Dec. 2000

Management of a Data Warehousing project for an Insurance Company which included leading a team of analysts, assisting analysts with roadblocks and project management.

Decision Consultants

Southfield, MI

Various contract consulting assignments included:

Responsibilities included analysis, development, testing, implementation, and user training and production support of the system using Oracle - SQL*Forms 3.0 in a UNIX environment, report Writer 2.5, Easel, PRO*C, Oracle 6.0, SQL*Forms 3.0 under VAX/VMS 5.5-2, Micro focus COBOL II and Micro focus Workbench

Faculties India

Bangalore, India Dec. 1989 to Dec. 1992

Responsibilities included analysis, development, testing, implementation, and user training and production support of the system using MF-COBOL under DOS, VAX-COBOL, VAX-DECFORMS, VAX-RDB under VMS, C, Informix-4GL.